Finding Aid for Clark Tibbitts Papers 1926-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Papers, Speeches, And Reprints 1926-1982
  - 1951
    - First National Conference on Aging (Box 5)
  - 1953 (Box 5)
  - 1954 (Box 5)
  - 1955 (Box 5)
  - 1956 (Box 5)
  - 1957-1958 (Box 5)
  - 1959 (Box 5)
  - 1960 (Box 5)
  - 1961 (Box 5)
  - 1962 (Box 5)
  - 1963 (Box 5)
  - 1964 (Box 5)
  - 1965 (Box 5)
  - 1966-1968 (Box 5)
  - 1969 (Box 5)
  - 1970-1982 (scattered) (Box 5)
  - undated (1986 accession) (Box 5)
- Correspondence
  (1986 accession)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 5)
  - 1958-1960 (Box 5)
  - 1961-1963, 1966-1968 (Box 5)
  - 1978, 1979, 1982 (Box 5)
  - re: Clark Tibbitts 1956, 1961 (Box 5)
- Publicity
  - Interview Transcripts undated, March 1962 (Box 6)
  - News clippings and Press Releases undated
    - 1955-1956 (Box 6)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 6)
    - 1959-1962, 1965, 1968 (Box 6)
- Awards and honors
  - Undated, 1957-1958 (Box 6)
- Publications 1950-1980
  - Journal and Magazine Publications undated, 1950-1951, 1954, 1957-1958, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Journal and Magazine Publications 1961 (Box 6)
  - Monographic Publication: Academic Gerontology: Dilemmas of the 1980s (chapter drafts and book), 1978-1980 (Box 6)
- Photographs
  (Titles taken from photographs)
  - Clark Tibbitts: "Speaker Hyde Park YMCA Tenth Anniversary Seniors" undated (Box 6)
  - Clark Tibbitts and three unidentified males: "Georgetown University Forum" undated (Box 6)
  - Clark Tibbitts and unidentified group: "White House Conference on Aging, Inducting Req. Refs. & T.D.'s," July 1959 (Box 6)
  - Clark Tibbitts: "Photo by staff photographer of the Denver Post," April 24, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Clark Tibbitts, Wilma Donahue and unidentified group: [Seminars in Social Gerontology for Faculty of Michigan Educational Institutions, Ann Arbor, MI 1968-1969 (Box 6)
- Inter-University Council Of Social Gerontology Training Programs; Summer Institute In Social Gerontology 1958-1959
  - Pre-conference planning (Box 6)
  - Announcements, program brochure (Box 6)
  - Lecture notes (Box 6)
  - Post conference comments (Box 6)
  - Draft Proposal 1962 (Box 6)
- Course Notes, etc.
  (Materials filed alphabetically by institution where presentation first given; Tibbitts often revised earlier files for use at later date at different institution)
  - American University
    - Course outlines and exams 1956-1959, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
    - Biology and Aging 1965, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Economic Status 1966 (Box 6)
    - Employment 1959, 1964, 1967, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Family 1955, 1959, 1965, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Health 1959, 1963, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Housing, Basic Considerations 1963, 1965, 1966, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Programs for Free Time 1963 (Box 6)
    - Retirement 1973 (Box 6)
    - Social and Economic Background 1962, 1965, 1967, 1968, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Use of Leisure Time 1968, 1973 (Box 6)
  - George Washington University
    - Appointment papers 1966-1968 (Box 6)
    - Course Outlines 1962-1968 (Box 6)
    - Aging & Economy & Budgets 1963, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Health Facilities 1967 (Box 6)
    - Personality 1965 (Box 6)
    - Politics of Age 1969 (Box 6)
    - Population Structure 1965, 1967, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Psychology 1962, 1963, 1965, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Social Organization 1973 (Box 6)
    - Societal Responsibility 1967 (Box 6)
  - Course Outlines/Exams Collected by Tibbitts from classes related to gerontology 1956-1973 (Box 6)
- Committee on Aging and Geriatrics
  - Progress Report 1951-1952 (Box 6)
  - Statement of Policy Regarding Department Program in Aging and Geriatrics March 1954 (Box 6)
  - Regional Institutes of Gerontology: A Proposal from the Administration on Aging December 1, 1967 (Box 6)